Giza, Egypt

Tasneem Toolba

Email Github

BIO

I've been working as a Mobile Engineer for over Three years and am currently actively seeking Blockchain Positions. I've recently shifted to Blockchain. Since then, I've participated in 4+ hackathons, attended Devcon 7 and ETHGlobal, and participated in the OnlyDust hackathon twice, the latest being the Aleph De Verano hackathon. I am also an active member of HERDAO and Arabs in Blockchain.

EMPLOYMENT

Mobile Engineer

EFinance

Aug 2023 - Current

- Develop mobile applications using the latest technologies in native Android.
- Maintain legacy Android projects
- Develop new Android projects(<u>this</u>) using the latest libraries such as Retrofit, Dagger Hilt, and a well-structured code for POSs
- Maintain water, gas, and electricity POS' C/C++ libraries and integration with Android apps
- Integrate Payment gateway and ECR protocol in the developed mobile apps using both soap messages and rest APIs

Software Engineer

AppNest

Sep 2023 - Aug 2024

- Write CI/CD to auto-deploy .net, node.js, Angular, and other application stacks to IIS(Windows), and nginx(Linux) using Yml files, Docker, and Kubernetes
- Write backend applications in node is

Flutter Developer

Hello Move(Netherlands)

Jan 2022 - Spring 2023

- Developed and maintained the company's service: available on (App Store, <u>Google Play</u>, & App Gallery).
- Use rest APIs to manage data in the app, GitHub Actions to auto-deploy the app to Google Play
- Use the latest state management apps like blocs for state management

Flutter Developer

DevStack(Russia)

Mar 2021 - Dec 2021

- Built various Flutter applications, utilizing Firebase apps and Diango for the backend.
- Integrate Google Maps, utilize Firebase and Firestore, integrate NFC detection and face detection

VOLUNTEERING

Open Source Contribution

Oct 2024 - Current

OnlyDust: Contribution To <u>Starknet Quest</u>, & <u>The Marquis Gaming</u>

C/C++ Couch

SOI2020(Saudi Arabia) EOI2020-EOI2023(Egypt) Sep-Dec 2020/June-Aug 2023

- Taught fundamentals of C/C++, competitive programming, algorithms, and data structures.
- Prepared students for national and international Informatics Olympiads.

EDUCATION

Innopolis, Republic of Tatarstan

Innopolis University

Fall 2019 - Jun 2023

B.S in Computer Science (GPA 4.5/5)

PROJECTS

- Wagmi-ERC-3770: an extension to Wagmi that extends the usage of erc-3770, won first place in optimism superchain interoperability track in Aleph De Vanero Hackathon
- <u>Cross-Chain uniswap mini app</u>: EthGlobal bangkok hackathon project, mini app swaps tokens cross-chain
- Compiler: A compiler for a user-defined functional programming language using C/C++.
- Digital Library: An online course content management system using Django and Vue.js.
- <u>InnoTutor</u>: A tutoring management app where students offer tutoring services in their areas of expertise and earn university digital currency, synchronized across other university websites using **Flutter**.
- FinnData: A stock app that allows you to search and receive information about stocks in Flutter.
- <u>RecipeSearch</u>: An app that helps you to find cuisine recipes; the Frontend was in **Typescript**,
 React

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND AWARDS

- Top 5 in the TV program "Cairo Innovates".
- Golden medalist, Silver medalist, and IOI qualification participant.
- First place in RoboGames.
- Intel ISEF participant.

LANGUAGES

- Cairo: Starknet Challenges & Speed runs challenges
- Solidity: Foundry & Hardhat, Cyfrin Solidity and Foundry courses, ERC20, ERC721, ERC1155
- **Python(Backend/Django, & web3/blockchain):** Junior <u>DynamicNFTMinterBot</u>, <u>DjangoProject</u>, <u>PrayerBot</u>, <u>Digital Library</u>, <u>Databases</u>.
- C/C++: Intermediate Compiler, Operating Systems, Matrix Fraction,
- Flutter/dart: WeatherApp, FormApplication, CleanHabits, OnlineChatRoom, FinnData, ChuckNorris
- DevOps(K8s, Terraform, Vagrant, Docker, & monitoring): Best Practice